有时候  童年对我来说如此遥远
Some days, my childhood feels so very far away.
其他时候
And others,
却又感觉历历在目
I can almost see it.
养育我的那片神奇土地
The magical land of my youth,
宛如一场美梦
like a beautiful dream
那时世界于我  有无限希望
of when the whole world felt like a promise
而未来的教训  尚未得预见
and the lessons that lay ahead yet unseen.
回顾童年  我真希望自己用心倾听
Looking back, I wish I'd listened.
真希望自己更仔细地
Wish I'd watched more closely
观察和体会
and understood.
但有时候  直到拨云见日
But sometimes you can't see what you're learning
才会豁然开朗
until you come out the other side.
快
Come on!
加油
来吧
Come on!
我得过去了
I'm gonna miss out.
我曾见证这比赛
I've seen this contest
令身经百战的勇士也低头  戴安娜
humble even the most seasoned warriors, Diana.
我能行
I can do it.
尽力就好
Just do your best.
你要记住
And remember,
伟大并非你所想的那样
greatness is not what you think.
找准节奏  耐心观察
Pace yourself and watch.
不
No!
不  这不公平
No! That's not fair!
不
No.
不...
No. But...
- 你走了捷径  - 但...
- You took the short path. - But...
- 你作弊了  戴安娜  - 不  但那...
- You cheated, Diana. - No. But that...
那才是真相
That is the truth.
是唯一的真相  真相就是一切
That is the only truth, and truth is all there is.
但我本来能赢的  要不是你...
But I would've won, if you didn't...
但你没有赢
But you didn't.
你不可能赢  因为你还没准备好
You cannot be the winner, because you are not ready to win,
这没什么好羞愧的
and there is no shame in that.
心中明知真相却拒绝接受
Only in knowing the truth in your heart
那才是可耻的
and not accepting it.
谎言中诞生不出真正的英雄
No true hero is born from lies.
你的胜利会到来的  戴安娜
Your time will come, Diana.
什么时候
When?
等你准备好后
When you're ready.
以黄金战士阿斯忒瑞亚为榜样
Look to the Golden Warrior Asteria.
她不是靠急功近利成为传奇的
She did not become a legend out of haste.
她凭借的是真正的勇敢之举
She did it through true acts of bravery.
比如耐心  勤勉
Like patience, diligence,
以及面对真相的勇气
and the courage to face the truth.
总有一天  你会实现自己的梦想  超出梦想
One day, you'll become all that you dream of and more,
那时一切都会不同
and everything will be different.
这个世界还没准备好迎接你未来的成就
This world is not yet ready for all that you will do.
《神奇女侠1984》
欢迎来到未来
Welcome to the future.
生活已很美好  但还可以更好
Life is good, but it can be better.
为什么不呢
And why shouldn't it be?
我们曾经梦想的一切  如今都唾手可得
Everything we've ever dreamed about is right at our fingertips.
但你的收获如何
But are you reaping the rewards?
你是否
Do you...
拥有了一切
have it all?
(可通行)
- 慢点  老兄  - 没门
- Slow down, dude. - No way.
老兄
Dude!
欢迎来到黑金合作社
Welcome to Black Gold Cooperative.
- 天啊  - 第一家由人民经营
- Oh, my gosh. Guys! - The first oil company
为人民服务的石油公司
run for the people, by the people.
试想终于能拥有你梦寐以求的一切
Think about finally having everything you've always wished for.
快走
Let's go!
只需每月付一点点费用
For a low monthly fee,
你就可以在世上最赚钱的行业中占分一杯羹
you can own a piece of the most lucrative industry in the world.
每次我们发财
And every time we strike gold,
你也一起发财
you strike gold.
不管你是谁  从事什么
No matter who you are, no matter what you do,
你都值得拥有一切
you deserve to have it all.
你是否拥有了梦寐以求的一切
Do you have everything you've ever wanted?
你是否厌倦了总是想要更多
Aren't you tired of always wishing you had more?
- 让开  该我了  - 今天就加入我们
- Hey, move it. It's my turn. - Join me today.
- 太棒了  - 接线员随时待命
- Yes! - Operators are standing by.
你不需要腰缠万贯
You don't need a pile of money or
或是商科毕业才能起步
some business degree to get started.
你甚至不用为之努力
You don't even have to work hard for it.
- 早上好  - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
别做小动作
Don't even think about it.
加入黑金合作社  你只需要
At Black Gold Cooperative, all you need
大胆去想
is to want it!
(黑金合作社)
我们拿了东西就会离开
We get what we want, and we go.
- 你们想要什么  - 不是这堆破烂
- What do you want? - None of this junk.
有传言说你们的黑市副业
Word is on the street you got a nice little black market
搞得风生水起
side business going on back there.
我们可以帮彼此保密
If you don't tell, we won't tell.
太好了  太好了
Yes, yes, yes!
谢谢  谢谢
Oh, thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
太好了  太好了
Yes, yes, yes!
先生  你还好吗
Sir, are you all right?
有枪
Gun!
他有枪
He's got a gun!
闭嘴  拜托
Shut up! Please!
走吧  藏不住了  我们快跑
Come on, dude. Can't hide. Let's get out of here!
站住  商场保安
Stop! Mall Security!
别动  就是你  你站住
No, no, you, you, right there!
站住  不许动  停下
Right there! Freeze. Stop!
让开  让开
Move, move, move!
老大  他们跑上扶梯了
Chief, they're running up the escalator.
站住  不许动
Stop! Freeze!
不许动
Freeze!
不
No!
有几名持械匪徒正在商场逃窜
We have several armed assailants running free.
我们需要警方立即支援
We need the police here, right now.
不许动
Freeze!
不许动  不许动
Freeze! Freeze!
别  老兄  冷静
No. Dude, dude, calm...
退后  否则我动手了
Get back, man. I'll do it!
你干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
没事的  会没事的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
你干什么
What are you doing?
Hey, what are you doing?
- 我不要回监狱  - 不不不
- I'm not going back! - No, no, no!
冷静  别冲动
Just chill out. Just chill.
- 退后  - 别这样
- Stand back! - Don't do it!
把孩子放下
Put the kid back.
听我说
Listen to me.
Listen to me!
- 不  - 你干什么
- No! - What are you doing?
把她拉上去  拉上去
Pull her back. Pull her back in!
我不要回监狱
I'm not going back!
不
No!
我要撒手了
Gonna let her go!
- 不  不  - 不
- No, no, no! - No, no!
什么  是谁  什么
What? Who? What?
今天可不玩那一套
We won't be doing that today.
我们  我们该走了
We... We... We should go...
天啊
Oh, my gosh!
抓紧
Hold tight.
我讨厌枪
I hate guns.
我们得走了  快点
We've got to go now. Come on.
我错了  女士
I'm sorry, lady.
我错了  行吗
I'm sorry. Okay?
都是他的主意
It was his idea.
当局还有不少疑问
And the authorities still have questions.
首当其冲的疑问就是
In fact, the first is a real doozy, which is,
究竟是谁阻止了这起犯罪
who exactly even stopped this crime?
如果现场流传的说法可信
If the story around here is to be believed,
那么阻止犯罪的不是警方
it wasn't the police,
而是多名目击者看到的
but a mysterious female savior
一位神秘的女性救星
that multiple witnesses saw.
如果这事听来耳熟  那就对了
If this sounds familiar, it should.
自去年以来  华盛顿及周边地区
We've now had more than a half-dozen similar sightings
发生了数起类似的目击事件
across the greater D.C. area in the last year.
这就引出了今天最大的疑问
Which, of course, begs the biggest question of today,
这位女士究竟是谁
who is this woman
她又来自哪里
and where did she come from?
(世界大战结束  鲁登道夫神奇落败  疑团重重)
(海外退伍军人协会表彰当地的英雄  英勇作战的飞行员史蒂夫·特雷弗)
(特雷弗农场)
打扰了  你在等人吗
Excuse me. Are you waiting for someone?
不  就我自己
No. Just me.
出租车
Taxi!
抱歉  我没注意到你
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't see you there.
你愿意的话我们可以拼车
Hey, we could share, if you like?
不了  谢谢  我再等等
No, thanks. I'll wait.
天啊
Oh, my.
杰克
Hey, Jake.
杰克  你好啊  能不能...
Jake, hi. Can you...
我知道  太笨拙了  搭扣突然...
I know, walk much? The latch of my...
早上好
Good morning.
你好  谢谢
Hi. Thank you.
我是戴安娜·普林斯  研究人类学和考古学
Diana Prince, cultural anthropology and archaeology.
我是芭芭拉·密涅瓦  研究地质学  宝石学  岩石学
Barbara Minerva. Geology, gemology, lithology,
也是兼职的神秘动物学家
and part-time cryptozoologist.
我大学期间没闲着
I kept busy in college.
抱歉  都怪这双高跟鞋  太蠢了
Sorry. It's these heels, you know. It's stupid.
真不知道我为什么要穿高跟鞋
I don't know why I was gonna wear heels.
科学家都不穿高跟鞋的
Scientists don't wear heels.
有时候也会穿
Sometimes we do.
- 确实  你的鞋真酷  - 祝你愉快
- Right. Those are cool! - Have a nice day.
我喜欢
I like those.
动物印花
Animal print.
你想一起吃午饭吗
Do you want to get lunch?
我...
I, uh...
当然不是现在
Not now, obviously.
现在还早  但今天晚些时候
It's morning. But later today, or whenever.
比如...午饭的时候
Like, around... Like, at lunchtime?
我今天有很多工作要忙
I have a lot of work today.
不过也许改天吧
But maybe some other time?
- 好的  我今天也很忙  - 好的
- Yeah, I'm busy today, too. - Great.
戴安娜  你知道芭芭拉·密涅瓦是谁吗
Diana, do you happen to know who a Barbara Minerva is?
你好  卡萝尔
Oh, hi, Carol. Hi.
是我  我就是芭芭拉  记得吗  你录用的我
It's me. I'm Barbara. Remember? You hired me.
我上周开始上班的
Started last week.
宝石学家
Gemologist?
对  也是动物学家
Yes. And zoologist.
- 我们面试了几次  - 嗯
- We had a couple interviews. - Yeah.
今天下午联调局
Well, the FBI are gonna drop off
会送来一些物品
some artifacts later this afternoon.
联调局
The FBI?
- 对  - 他们要来这里
- Yeah. - They're coming here?
昨天的商场劫案
The mall heist yesterday,
据说那家珠宝店是个幌子
apparently they were using a jewelry store as a front.
什么的幌子
Front for what?
黑市  向私人买家出售被盗珠宝和艺术品
Black market. Stolen jewels and art meant for private buyers.
不过有一件物品需要你来帮助鉴定
But we could use your help identifying one in particular.
需要我  好啊  我愿意帮助联调局
My help? Yeah, I'll help the FBI
- 尽我所能  - 你这是答应了吗
- with whatever they need. - Is that a yes?
是的  我...
Yes. I would, um...
- 我很乐意协助你  - 太好了
- I would love to assist you. - Wonderful.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you.
我们已经认识过了
We've met.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
再见  戴安娜
Bye, Diana.
好了  23号物品
Okay, item number 23.
见鬼  不是这个
Shoot. That's not it.
暹罗女皇
The Empress of Siam.
最初发现于阿卡托夫人号沉船的残骸中
Originally found in the wreck of the Nuestra Senora de Atocha.
抱歉  我忍不住想来看看
Sorry. I couldn't resist coming to see.
没关系
Oh, it's okay.
找到了
Here it is.
是什么
What is it?
我看不出来
I can't tell.
来点灯光
Some light.
我觉得用专业术语来说应该是
I think the technical term here
"超级没劲"
is "extremely lame."
这是黄水晶
It's... It's citrine.
从古至今广泛用于造假的石头
A classic stone used in fakes throughout history.
我看这东西价值最多75美元
I can't imagine this is worth any more than $75.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
鉴伪不是我的专长  不过我来看看
Fakes aren't my forte, but let me see.
拉丁语
Latin.
好歹是个古董吧
At least it's an antique, right?
也可能是上周在佛罗伦萨老桥上的摊位买的
Or a purchase from a stall on the Ponte Vecchio last week.
谁知道呢
You never know.
"握持此物  许一宏愿"
"Place upon the object held but one great wish."
你会拉丁语
You read Latin?
是的  语言算是我的爱好
Yeah. Yeah. Languages are a hobby.
也许这是个幸运物
So maybe it's, like, a lucky charm or something?
大概是吧
Yeah, I guess.
真奇怪
Strange.
我真希望能喝杯咖啡
I really wish I had a coffee.
你真幽默
You're funny.
我给艾瑞卡买了杯咖啡  但她请病假了
Hey, I got Erika a coffee, but she's out sick.
有人要喝吗
Does anybody want this?
什么  好啊  我来喝
What? Yeah, I'll take one.
烫  好烫
Ooh, hot! Hot, hot!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
如果这是真货  你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
如果是真货就好了
If only.
愿望太多  我都不知道该许哪一个
So many things, I don't even know what I would wish for.
我知道
I do.
好了  抱歉打扰你了
Well, um, anyway, sorry to bother you.
如果你有需要  随时可以找我
If you need anything, I'm around.
好的  现在没事
Oh, yeah, I'm good.
谢谢你刚刚...
But thank you for...
不用客气  这是我的工作
That's okay. It's my job.
等我有机会了再深入研究
And I'll look into it more when I have a chance.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你...
Well, thanks for...
主动跟我说话
talking to me.
真不好意思
I'm... I'm sorry, uh...
我没事了
I mean, I'm fine.
话说  我们可以早点去吃晚饭
You know, we could go and grab early dinner
聊聊这块石头有多没劲
and talk about exactly how lame that stone is.
真的吗
Really?
真的  黄水晶  不是吧
Yeah, I mean, citrine?
这能唬住谁啊
Who are they kidding, right?
- 太没劲了  - 真傻
- So lame. - Dorky.
- 超没劲  - 是啊  我们走
- Lame. - Yeah, let's go.
真是没劲中的没劲
That's, like, the lamest of lames.
你太幽默了
You're so funny.
谢谢
Thank you.
已经很久没人让我笑得这么痛快了
I mean, no one's made me laugh like this in such a long time.
确实  我不怎么出门社交
I mean, it's true, I don't get out much socially.
- 你不怎么出门  - 对  不常出门
- You don't get out much? - No, not really.
- 对  - 抱歉  我有点惊讶
- No. - I'm sorry. I'm just surprised.
因为你看起来像是那种
Because you just seem like the kind of person
从不回家的人
who's, like, always out.
天天都有人约你出去
Like, people are asking you to go out all the time
你经常出门  总在外面
and you live out. You're just out.
从来不待在家里
Like, you never get in.
你看起像是非常受欢迎的人
You just seem like you'd be really popular.
我能看出来  因为我从来都不受欢迎
And I would know because I've never been popular.
你不受欢迎
You haven't?
你这么好相处
You're so personable.
这么自由
So... free.
说真的  我挺羡慕你的
I mean, honestly, I gotta say that I envy that.
什么
What?
你羡慕我  这根本说不通
You envy me? That doesn't make any sense.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
大家觉得我很奇怪
People think I'm weird.
他们当面躲着我  背后说我坏话
They avoid me and talk behind my back
以为我听不见
when they don't think I can hear them.
我真想说  "我听得一清二楚"
I'm like, "Guys, I can hear you."
芭芭拉  我的生活
Barbara, my life
大概和你想象的不太一样
hasn't been what you probably think it has.
我们都有自己的难处
We all have our struggles.
是啊
Yeah, we do.
你谈过恋爱吗
Have you ever been in love?
谈过
Yeah.
很久很久以前
A long, long time ago.
你呢
You?
我是情场老手了
So many times, yeah. All the time.
真的
Often.
后来如何了
So what happened?
你男友  他去哪了
Where'd he go, your guy?
他...
He, uh...
他死了
He died.
但有时我抬头仿佛还能看到他在天上
But I still think sometimes that I see him up there in the sky.
他是飞行员
He was a pilot.
他有很多特点
He was all kinds of things,
但他真的很好
but he was great. It was true.
我懂
I get it.
为我们干杯
Well, cheers to us.
祝我们好运
Wishing us better luck, I guess.
里昂
Hey, Leon.
你好  芭芭拉  又加班吗
Hey there, Barbara. Late night?
对  正要回去工作
Yeah. Going back to work.
我想趁热把这个给你
I wanted to bring this to you while it was still hot.
- 你对我太好了  - 举手之劳
- You're too good to me. - It's not a problem.
注意保暖
Stay warm.
你好  甜心  要我帮你吗
Hey there, sweetheart. You need some help?
不用  我没事  谢谢
No, I'm fine. Thank you.
因为
'Cause, uh,
你穿高跟鞋走起来
you know, you look as though you're having
好像不太灵活
a little bit of trouble walking in those heels, huh?
没事  我天天穿高跟鞋
It's okay. I wear these heels all the time.
来吧  我送你回家
Hey, come on. Let me walk you home.
- 我不是要回家  - 我这是出于好心
- I'm not going home. - Hey, I'm just trying to be nice here.
来吧
Come on.
你干什么
What are you doing?
放开我
Let go of me!
- 我只是想帮你  - 放开我  放开我
- I'm just trying to help you! - Let go of me! Let go of me!
放手
Let go!
幸好我忘拿钥匙了
Forgot my keys. Lucky.
- 你怎么...  - 简单的自卫术
- How did you... - Simple self-defense.
借力打力  我可以教你
Used his own momentum against him. I'll teach you.
真的  完全不费力
Honestly, it takes no power at all.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
- 嗯  - 那就好
- Yeah. Yeah. - Alright.
- 谢谢你  - 别客气
- Thank you. - Of course.
- 快回家吧  - 好
- Go home, okay? - Yeah.
晚安
Good night.
我知道我会许什么愿
I do know what I'd wish for.
我希望像戴安娜一样
To be like Diana.
强大  性感
Strong, sexy,
潇洒
cool.
特别
Special.
糟了
Oh, no!
抱歉
Sorry.
没事
Oh, it's okay.
芭芭拉  幸亏你穿高跟鞋也很灵活
Barbara, thank God you're good in heels.
- 芭芭拉  - 杰克
- Hey, Barbara. - Hi, Jake.
气色不错
Looking good.
谢谢
Thanks.
这是我们的地球科学实验室
This is our Earth Sciences lab.
芭芭拉
Oh, Barbara!
你好
Hi.
太好了
Perfect.
我想给你介绍一个人
I have someone I would like you to meet.
幸会  密涅瓦女士
A pleasure, Ms. Minerva.
其实可以叫我博士
It's "Doctor," actually.
我们以前见过吗  你看着很面熟
Have we met before? You look familiar.
- 来一段  来一段  - 不
- Do the thing. Do the thing. - No.
生活已很美好  但还可以更好
Life is good, but it can be better.
天啊  电视上那个人
Oh, my gosh. From TV.
天啊  你是那个挖石油的
Oh, my gosh. You're the oil guy.
- "挖石油的"  这称号可以  - 对
- "The oil guy." I'll take it. - That's right.
罗德先生正在考虑
Mr. Lord is considering
成为史密森尼博物馆的高级资助人
becoming a Friend of the Smithsonian at the Partner level.
所以我们为他开放了
Which entitles him to a handful
一些私下参观活动
of private tours of our facilities,
他点名请你陪同
and he asked for you by name.
- 我吗  - 我能说什么呢  博士
- Me? - Well, what can I say, Doctor?
你可是声名远扬
Your reputation precedes you.
而且我们都对宝石学有浓厚的兴趣
And apparently we share a passion for gemology.
- 确实如此  - 那你们聊吧
- Okay. We do. - I'll leave you to it.
我先把这个放办公室  然后再陪你参观
Oh, let me just drop this off in my office, and we'll go.
天啊  别看  里面乱糟糟的
Oh, gosh. Don't look in there. It's such a mess.
我们可以从楼上开始参观
So, I thought maybe we could start upstairs.
这红宝石我喜欢
I love that ruby.
不  小心点
Oh, no. Be careful with that.
- 怎么了  - 这非常...
- What? - That's very...
你见到我朋友了吗  他去哪里了
Hey, have you seen my friend? Where'd he go?
- 我就在这里  - 是吗
- I'm right here. - You are.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
等等  你身上有点灰尘
Oh, wait. You've got a little dust on you.
- 抱歉  - 早上好
- Sorry. - Hey, good morning.
这位是独一无二的
This is the one and only,
麦克斯韦尔·罗德先生
Mr. Maxwell Lord.
就是他
It's him.
生活已很美好
Life is good,
但还可以更好
but it can be better.
电视上那个人
He's from TV.
我没有电视
I don't have a TV.
我和希尔斯百货关系很好
Well, I have a great relationship with Sears.
今天就能给你送一台崭新电视
I can get you a brand-new TV by the end of the day.
十九英寸
Nineteen inches.
- 无条件赠送  - 我觉得没有电视就挺好
- No strings attached. - I'll stick to the one I don't have.
不过谢谢好意
But thank you.
- 好吧  - 你真慷慨
- Okay. - You're so generous.
有大消息
Headline...
罗德先生
Mr. Lord
考虑要成为资助人
took a tour of the entire Smithsonian
然后参观了整座博物馆
while considering partnership,
猜猜他决定怎么做
and guess what he decided to do?
把他的全部捐款指名赠予我们部门
Give his entire donation to our department.
他会在今晚的资助人晚会上宣布
He's announcing it at tonight's Members' Gala.
今晚的派对肯定很精彩
It's going to be an amazing party.
希望你有拿得出手的衣服
I hope you have something nice to wear.
其实我一般不参加这些活动
I actually tend to skip these events.
那些真正乐善好施的资助人
I find that our benefactors with a true eye towards philanthropy
往往会远离聚光灯
prefer to stay out of the spotlight.
把关注度让给博物馆的成果
To let the museum's work garner the attention.
我同意
I agree.
只是
Except,
我喜欢派对
I like to party.
天啊  你舞跳得真好
Oh, my gosh. You're such a good dancer.
- 你喜欢拉丁舞吗  - 可喜欢了
- You like Latin dancing? - I love it.
我知道我跳得很差劲
I know that I'm a terrible dancer.
我才不相信你跳得差劲
No, I doubt that you're a terrible dancer...
- 真的  我高中时把髋扭伤了  - 你身材这么好
- No, I've got a hip injury from high school. - ...the shape that you're in.
好的
Great, so,
谢谢你来一趟
thank you so much for coming.
我真的该走了
You know, I really should be going.
谢谢你陪我参观
Thank you for the tour.
今晚你一定要来
I will have to see you tonight.
晚上见
See you tonight.
再见  祝你愉快
Bye. Have a good day.
不见不散
I'll find you.
怎么了
What?
我喜欢他
I like him.
谢谢  约翰
Thank you, John.
女士们
Ladies.
罗德先生
Mr. Lord.
我没空  拉克尔  我的补充剂呢
Not now, Raquel. My supplements?
在你桌上  但是罗德先生
On your desk, but Mr. Lord.
罗德先生
Mr. Lord.
(石油经济学人  新原油之王)
(新原油之王  赛义德·本·阿比多斯酋长  成为世界最大的私人石油所有者)
(逾期拖欠)
(最后要求)
罗德先生
Mr. Lord.
爸爸
Dad!
什么
How?
你怎么来了
How!
这周末你要陪孩子
It's your weekend.
我看出来了
Yes, clearly.
阿里斯特
Alistair.
泳池在哪里  爸爸
Where's the pool, Daddy?
还没建好呢  伙计
It's not done yet, buddy.
但那不重要
But it doesn't matter.
你得耐心点
You just have to be patient.
我说过  泳池
I told you the pool,
直升机
the helicopter,
都会是你的  但是记住
you'll have it all. But remember,
罗马不是一天建成的  对吧
Rome wasn't built in a day, was it? No.
但是已经过去很多天了吧
Hasn't it been a lot of days?
你爸爸要成为超凡卓绝的头号人物
Well, it takes time to become a great, great, number-one man,
这是要花时间的
like your dad is going to be.
不仅骗别人  还要骗儿子吗
Are you lying to your son, like you lie to everyone else?
西蒙
Simon.
办公室还没有做好待客准备
These offices aren't ready for guests yet.
结束了  麦克斯
It's over, Max.
我不想听了  我要退出
I don't want to hear it anymore. I'm out.
阿里斯特  去找拉克尔
Alistair, go wait with Raquel.
西蒙
Simon.
我知道你现在很难明白
I know it's hard to see right now, but
但是我们终于
we are finally right
快要扭转局面了
at the edge of turning this thing around.
"扭转局面"
"Turning it around"?
根本没有石油  从来就没有
There is no oil. There never was.
你打算怎么扭转局势
So how are you gonna turn it around?
再去骗几个我这样的倒霉投资人吗
Get more sucker investors, like me?
- 这叫庞氏骗局  - 不是
- It's called a Ponzi scheme. - No!
我有个大...
I have a big...
我的计划正在进行中
There's something in the works.
而且不是骗局
And it's no scheme.
西蒙  我们有数百万英亩的潜在油田
Simon, we have millions of acres of potentially oil-rich land.
你的石油开采权
You have oil rights on land
都是在别人放弃不要的土地上
that everyone else passed on already.
查清这事没费多少功夫
Now, it didn't take much digging to find that out.
我也该早点查查你的底细
I should have done some digging on you, too,
麦克斯韦尔·罗伦扎诺
Maxwell Lorenzano.
没用多久就查出来
Didn't take long to find out you're nothing
你不过是个卑劣的骗子
but a lowlife con man.
我不是骗子
I am not a con man!
我是电视名人
I am a television personality.
还是备受尊敬的商人
And a respected businessman
- 我有计划  - 别扯了
- with a plan. - Come on.
我有宏大的计划
With... With... With a great plan.
"只要敢想  就能实现"
"If you can dream it, you can have it."
这种计划吗
Something like that?
限你48小时内
You have 48 hours
- 把钱还给我  - 你会后悔的
- to get my money... - You're going to regret this.
否则联邦贸易委员会将收到匿名举报
...or the FTC gets an anonymous report.
- 窝囊废  - 西蒙  等等
- Loser. - Simon, wait.
西蒙  等等
Simon, wait.
我不是窝囊废
I am not a loser.
他才是窝囊废
He's a loser!
千万不要相信那个人说的话
And don't you ever believe a word that man said.
他是骗子
He's a liar...
而且他错了
and he's wrong.
他会后悔离开了我
And he will rue the day he walked away from me.
而你
And you...
你会为有我这个爸爸而骄傲
You are going to be so proud to be my son.
好吧
Okay.
你会明白的
You'll see.
所有人都会明白
Everyone will.
(罗马文化)
(已付款  麦克斯·罗德  黑金)
(黑金合作社  麦克斯·罗德)
这双鞋是出了名地合脚
These are known for a terrific fit.
嗯  但我穿高跟鞋走不稳
Yeah, I'm just not so great with heels.
试试看
Just try them.
出来让我看看
Come out and show me.
好吧
Okay.
确实很合脚
They do fit well.
我喜欢
Yeah, I like it.
你真美
You look amazing.
会不会太紧了
Do you think it's too tight?
我觉得恰到好处
I think it's just right.
我买了
I'll take it.
你好  近来如何
Hey there. How are you doing?
- 这双鞋真漂亮  - 谢谢
- Those shoes are incredible. - Thank you.
- 好美的裙子  - 你真漂亮
- What a beautiful dress. - You look fantastic.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
密涅瓦博士
Dr. Minerva.
你看起来太惊艳了
You look breathtaking.
谢谢
Thank you.
我...我们经常要
I... You know, we have to
来这种场合应酬
go to these sort of things for work a lot,
所以这条裙子我穿过无数次了
so I've probably worn this dress a million times.
其实不是的
Actually, no. I...
我今天才买的
I just bought this today.
我从没这么打扮过  从来没有
I never look like this. Um, not even close.
我花了好长时间才准备好
Took me a long time to get ready.
生物素
Biotin.
你应该试试
You should try it.
能让你像少女般容光焕发
Makes you glow like a teenager.
重返青春
Reverses the clock.
永远不要接受自然的局限性
Never accept the limitations of nature.
没错
Yeah, no.
尤其是你这样的漂亮女人
Especially not a beautiful woman like you.
天啊  这里太吵了
God, it's so loud in here.
是啊
Yeah.
我们能换个地方吗
Can we go somewhere?
- 只有我和你  - 好
- Just me and you? - Yes.
去你办公室吧
Your office?
看看这些东西  太...
Look at all of this stuff. It's so...
太美了
It's so beautiful.
像你一样
Like you.
那是什么
What is that?
不是什么特别的东西  真的
It's nothing special, really.
但联调局让我帮他们鉴定它
But the FBI did ask me to help them identify it.
不过到目前为止  我毫无头绪
Though it certainly has me stumped so far.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
麦克斯来了  马上帮你理清头绪
Max is here. No need to be stumped ever again.
我有个好朋友  很了解罗马古物
I have a dear friend in Roman antiquities.
- 罗马古物  - 如果你愿意  可以帮你看看
- Roman antiquities. - Could give it a look, if you like?
上面是拉丁语吧
It is Latin, isn't it?
我真的不能让它离开博物馆
I really shouldn't let it go out of the museum.
- 你好  美人  - 不了  谢谢  失陪
- Hey there, beautiful. - No, thank you. Excuse me.
戴安娜
Diana.
正希望能见到你呢
Hoping I'd see you.
你知道我目前在白宫工作吗
Hey, do you know I'm at the White House now?
是的  没错
Yeah, that's right.
还在实习  但是点名请我去的
Interning, but requested by name, so...
听着  我关注你有一段时间了
Listen, I've had my eyes on you for some time.
- 如果你需要...  - 太好了  卡尔
- So if you ever need... - That's great, Carl.
戴安娜
Diana.
不好意思  我根本不认识你  别再跟着我了
Excuse me, I don't even know you, so please stop following me.
- 晚安  - 但是...
- Good night. - But...
真希望我们能有更多时间
I wish we had more time.
你为什么说这句话
Why did you say that?
别对我说这句话
Don't say that to me.
你根本不认识我
You don't even know me.
我认识
Yes, I do.
我来拯救今天
I can save today...
你来拯救世界
but you can save the world.
史蒂夫
Steve?
戴安娜
Diana.
怎么可能
But how?
我不知道
I don't know.
天呐
Oh, my God.
是你
It's you.
我好想你
I missed you.
你还记得什么
So what do you remember?
我记得...
I remember...
我记得把飞机开上天
I remember taking the plane up...
然后
and then...
就什么都不记得了
nothing, really.
一片空白
Nothing.
但我却知道自己之后就去了一个地方
But somehow, I know I've been someplace since then.
一个...
Someplace that's, uh...
我难以形容
I can't really put words to it.
但很好的地方
But it's... It's good.
然后我在这里醒来
And then I, uh... I woke up here.
哪里
Where?
一张床上
I ended up in a bed.
奇奇怪怪的床  软绵绵的  架在板条上
Strange, strange pillow bed with slats.
- 那是床垫  - 床垫
- A futon, yeah. - A futon?
- 对  - 好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
不太舒适  感觉时代有点倒退了
Well, not comfortable. And really a bit backwards
我和你说实话
if I'm being really honest with you.
毕竟现在是未来时代了  现在是19...
I mean, for a futuristic time like this. Nineteen...
84年  1984年
Eighty-four. 1984.
太惊人了
That's amazing.
你想来看看我的床垫吗
Would you like to see my futon?
好吧
Yeah. Um...
不用你多说
You don't have to tell me.
这地方乱糟糟的
The place is a mess.
瓶装奶酪
Cheese on demand.
我一上午都在打扫他的卧室
I spent all morning cleaning his bedroom, but
他似乎是个工程师
he seems to me to be an engineer.
有很多他自己的照片
Lots of pictures of himself.
我不会干这种事  但人各有所好吧
Not what I would do, but to each his own.
你就是这样找到我的
So this is how you found me.
对  用电话簿
Yeah, the phone book.
有些东西永远不过时
I guess some things are just future-proof.
你去我家找我了吗
So you went to my apartment?
对  一开始我想骑这辆单车去
Yeah, I tried to use the bike at first.
但不管我怎么蹬它都原地不动
I couldn't really figure out how to get it going,
所以我跑过去了  正好看到你回家
so I ran over and saw you come back.
然后我惊呆了
And I was stunned.
你就在眼前
There you were.
于是我就...
So I just, uh...
像个变态一样跟踪了你
followed you, like a creep.
戴安娜  看看你...
Diana, look at you. It's...
时光没留下一丝痕迹
It's like not one day has passed.
你可是大变样了
I can't say the same thing about you.
是啊  是啊
Right, right, right. Right.
嗯  他...
Yeah, he's, uh...
他还行吧
He's got it.
我喜欢他
No, I like him.
他挺好  但我眼中只有你
He's great, but all I see is you.
"许一宏愿"  我盼望已久了
"One great wish." I've been waiting.
我希望成为你
I wish to be you.
梦想石本身
The Dreamstone itself.
过来
Come here.
- 早上好  - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
我醒来后一直在吃果酱馅饼
Been eating Pop-Tarts all morning,
还喝了大概三壶咖啡
and I've had about three, three pots of coffee.
这地方太棒了
This place is amazing.
- 这地方  - 是啊
- This place? - Yeah.
好好想想的话
You know, if I really think about it,
我从没住过比这更棒的房间
I don't think I've ever been in a room more amazing.
- 你说得对  - 是啊
- It's true. - Yeah.
这是我这辈子住过最棒的房间
This room is the most amazing place I've ever been in, in my entire life.
这地方真的是最棒的  对吧
It is the most amazing place, right?
所以我们应该待在这里不走了
So let's, let's stay. We shouldn't go.
- 我真的不想走  - 所以别走了
- I really don't want to. - So, let's not.
- 好  - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
我们就待在这里
Let's just stay here.
永远
Forever.
但是
Although...
我或许应该去查清楚
I should probably go and figure out
一块石头是怎么借用别人的身体
how a stone brought my boyfriend back
把我的男友带回来了
in someone else's body.
有道理  走吧
That's a fair point. Let's go.
斯塔格先生
Mr. Stagg?
谢谢  贝琳达
Thank you, Belinda.
天呐
Oh, God.
你最好是来还我钱的
You'd better be here with my money.
我会还你钱的  西蒙  但要先道歉
I'll have your money, Simon. Today, I'm here for an apology.
你疯了吗  我才不会道歉呢
Are you out of your mind? I'm not going to apologize.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我搞砸了  我搞砸了  我骗了你
I messed up. I messed up. I lied.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
事实上  我早就知道我们会血本无归
You know, the truth is, i knew we were going to sink a long time ago.
探测油井一无所获
The wells were coming up dry.
也没有数据提示可能发现石油
And no data suggested that was going to change.
那时我就应该收手的
I should have folded then.
但是为了所有入伙的人  相信我的人
But all the people that bought in, that believed in me.
- 我想要扭转乾坤  - 拜托
- I wanted to do right. - Oh, come on.
麦克斯  你不用...
Max, look, you don't have to...
西蒙  你难道不理解我希望成就更多吗
Simon, don't you understand that I wished for better?
我体内的每一个细胞
That with every ounce of my being,
都希望黑金能为我们所有人改变这个世界
I wished that Black Gold would change the world for all of us.
我知道这也是你的愿望
And I know you wished that, too.
这当然也是我的愿望
Of course I wished that, too.
那么你的愿望实现了
Then your wish is granted.
作为回报  你这个阻碍
And in return, I'll take all of your shares...
会被神奇地铲除掉
and full control of Black Gold,
将黑金公司的股份和控制权全部交给我
after you are somehow magically removed from my path...
- 你说什么  - 永远不回来
- You're gonna what? - ...forever.
麦克斯
Max!
Hey, Max!
回来  麦克斯
Get back here! Max!
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
我们有西蒙·斯塔格的拘捕令
We have a warrant for Simon Stagg.
天呐  我们有危险吗
My word. Are we in danger?
没事  先生  这是联邦税务犯罪
No, sir. Federal taxation crime.
与你无关  快走吧
It doesn't concern you. Move along.
让他们过去
Send them through.
- 好  跟我来  - 我们走
- Okay. Follow me. - Let's go, guys.
你说这一切的源头是一块石头
So you said a stone started all of this?
对  这正是我们要调查的
Yeah, that's what we need to go and find out.
肯定跟它脱不了关系
I mean, it must have done something.
这身棒极了
This is dynamite.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
- 还行吧  - 是吧
- Yeah. Yeah... - Huh? Right?
我在杂志上看到过  袖子要卷上去
I saw a couple of magazine pictures. They roll these up.
应该还有更好的
I think we can do better.
看看这些口袋  这里有口袋
Look at all the pockets in this. There are pockets here.
这条裤子上到处都是口袋
There are pockets all over the pant.
位置可调的美国式腰包
American issue bag, adjustable.
降落伞裤
Parachute pants?
- 嗯  - 现在人人都会跳伞吗
- Yeah. Uh... - Does everybody parachute now?
其实我对这身不太感冒
You know, I'm not so keen on this one.
但我觉得你会喜欢  就这身吧
I figure you are, but you know what, I'm ready to go.
- 如何  - 不行
- Right? - No.
- 你看都不看一眼  - 不合适
- You're not even giving it a second. - It's not good.
太夸张吗  是惊人还是吓人
"Too much" in a good way or a bad way? Right?
太吓人
In a bad way.
这才像样
Now that's great.
太好看了
It's beautiful.
是吗  我绝不会穿这身出门
Yeah. I would absolutely never wear it.
- 我像是个海盗  - 史蒂夫
- I feel like a pirate. - Steve.
谁会穿成这样
Who would wear this?
戴安娜
Diana,
你快看这双鞋
have you seen these shoes?
- 鞋就穿着吧  - 鞋可以穿  太好了
- Let's keep the shoes. - Let's keep the shoes. Yes!
- 鞋没问题  - 太棒了
- Let's keep the shoes. - Yes!
这个有点特别
This is a special one, okay?
我们一起来
Let's do this together.
一脚先  一脚后
One foot after the other.
站在这一节上
Now stay on this one.
站到中间
Go to the middle.
别  史蒂夫
No, Steve...
史蒂夫  你会摔下去的
Steve, you're gonna fall.
我真的以为会摔下去呢
I really thought I was gonna fall.
你好呀
What's up?
这是霹雳舞
This is break dance.
- 这也算舞蹈  - 没错
- Dancing? - Yeah.
别紧张
Don't worry.
- 没事的  只是个舞蹈动作  - 是吗
- It's fine. It's just a move. - Yeah?
没事的
It's nothing.
这些都是艺术品
It's all art.
好
Yeah.
这是垃圾桶
That's just a trash can.
这是垃圾桶  好  好
It's just a trash can. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
那是飞机吗
Is that a plane?
来  我带你参观一下
Come on. I want to show you something.
太不可思议了
This is incredible!
每次我们发财
And every time we strike gold,
你也一起发财
you strike gold.
试想终于能拥有你梦寐以求的一切
Think about finally having everything you've always wished for.
拉克尔
Raquel?
黑金合作社  请稍等
Black Gold. Can you hold, please?
黑金合作社  是的  请稍等
Black Gold. Yes. Hold, please.
- 拉克尔  - 请稍等
- Raquel? - Hold, please.
油井挖到石油了
The wells struck pay!
- 哪个油井  - 全部
- Which ones? - All of them.
投资人不知从哪里得到的消息
And the investors heard about it somehow.
全都打电话来追加投资
They're calling to up their buys.
他们的朋友也打来要入股
Their friends are calling to buy in.
不知从哪里冒出很多新的投资人
New investors are calling out of thin air.
请稍等  我需要帮手
Hold on, please. I need more help.
- 黑金合作社  请稍等  - 我给你找帮手
- Black Gold. Can you hold, please? - I'll get you help.
再跟我说一次  你希望有更多帮手吗
Tell me again. You wish you had more help?
对  我希望有更多帮手
Yes, I wish I had more help.
电话太多接不过来了
There are just too many calls to take.
你好
Hi.
抱歉打扰
I'm sorry to bother you.
我本来要去一家会计公司面试
I'm meant to be interviewing at an accounting firm.
你被录用了
You're hired!
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard!
- 我是爱默生  - 爱默生
- Emerson. - Emerson!
这里是就业中心吗
Is this the employment office?
没错  你也被录用了
Yes! You're hired, too!
罗德先生  是《华尔街日报》
Mr. Lord, it's Wall Street Journal.
他们想就公司的突然翻盘来采访你
They want to interview you about company's sudden surge.
我去我的办公室接
I'll take it in my office.
把我的维生素拿来
And bring me my vitamins.
我昨晚真的读了四本书
So I did read about four books last night...
试图把这玩意研究透彻
to try to get to the bottom of this.
然后我发现  罗杰你是对的
And did find out, Roger, you were right.
这个确实是宋代的
This is from the Song Dynasty.
你是对的
You were correct.
另外有趣的是
And also interesting,
我昨晚看了几本百科全书  你...
I was looking at a couple of encyclopedias last night and you...
谢谢
Thanks.
真奇怪  看这么多书
So funny, all this reading seems
似乎把我的近视眼治好了
to have cured my eyesight somehow.
有趣的是  我们...
Interesting fact which we...
早上好
Good morning.
这是史蒂夫  他是我的...
This is Steve. He's my, um...
- 老朋友  - 对
- Old friend. - Yeah.
你好  老朋友史蒂夫
Hi, old friend Steve.
我是芭芭拉  戴安娜的新朋友
I'm Barbara, Diana's new friend.
你是做什么的
So what do you do?
我是飞行员
I'm a pilot.
- 飞行员  那不是...  - 我能跟你谈几句吗
- Pilot? Isn't that... - Can I speak to you for a second?
好的
Sure.
我只是想跟你谈谈那块石头
So, I just wanted to speak to you about that stone.
那块黄水晶
The citrine one.
它还在你这里吗
Do you have it?
这事说来话长
Long story, actually, about that.
麦克斯·罗德昨天来了一趟
Max Lord came by to visit yesterday.
还挺愉快的
Which was actually pretty great.
之后再跟你细说
I'll tell you about it later.
我把石头
I let him
借给他了
borrow it.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
戴安娜
Well, Diana,
他才给我们捐了一大笔钱
he just gave us a huge amount of money.
他又不是什么陌生人
It's not like he's a stranger or anything.
而且他有个朋友是专家  于是...
Plus he has a friend who's an expert, and I don't know...
你在说什么  你怎么能借出去呢
What do you mean? How could you loan it?
那根本不是我们的东西
It's not even ours to loan.
你干嘛冲我嚷嚷
What are you getting on my case for?
我办公室多得是比那石头珍贵的东西
I've got 15 things in my office more valuable than that stone.
你知道他把石头拿去哪了吗
Do you know where he took it?
完全不知道
No, I have no idea.
那我们有发现再通知你
Then I'll tell you what we find out.
走吧
Let's go.
- 我很喜欢你的裤子  - 谢了
- I like your pants very much. - Oh, thanks.
记得打给我
Yeah. Call me.
不打也行  随便吧
Or not. Whatever.
但我想听后续
But I'd be curious.
请拨打黑金热线
Call the Black Gold hotline.
此处不售卖股票
Shares are not available in the building.
这些人在干什么
What are these people doing?
不管怎样
Whatever it is,
从那条路是进不去了
we're not getting in that way.
戴安娜  戴安娜  走这边
Diana. Diana, this way.
你请便
Have at it.
好结实的锁
Strong lock.
史蒂夫
Steve.
- 落满了灰尘  - 是啊
- It's so dusty. - Yeah.
跟爆炸现场似的
It's like a bomb went off.
(商场劫案涉案古物运往史密森尼博物馆  有消息称珍贵文物失而复得)
不论这是什么  他已经找了很久了
Whatever this is, he's been looking for it for a long time.
"握持此物"
"Place upon the object held."
怎么了
What is it?
这是众神的语言
The language of the Gods.
问题是  这是哪个神写的
Which God wrote it, is the question.
- 谢了  - 不客气
- Thanks. Oh, yeah. - Yeah. It's okay.
我还有点事  回头再聊  好吗
I gotta go do something. Okay. I'll talk to you. All right?
- 喂  - 芭芭拉  我需要你的帮助
- Hello? - Barbara, I need your help.
我需要你找出
I need you to find out
那块石头被发现的确切地点
exactly where that stone was found.
我要知道地点  明白吗
"Where" is what I need to know. You understand?
明白  我这就着手
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
谢谢
Thanks.
你的表情像撞见鬼了
You look like you saw a ghost.
的确撞见了
I did.
世上曾经有很多神
There were many Gods
他们出于不同的目的做不同的事
and they did different things for different reasons.
其中一件事就是制造这样的物品
One was making objects like this.
这个世界中有许多通用元素
There are universal elements in this world,
当它们被注入容器之中
and when they're imbued into something,
就会变得强大无比
they can become very, very powerful.
比如我的真言套索
Like my Lasso of Truth.
它的力量源泉是真相  而不是我
The truth is what powers it, not me.
真相的力量比我们都强大
The truth is bigger than all of us.
但是什么给了它力量
But what is this?
我不知道
I don't know. Uh...
既然能带我回来
Brought me back.
也许是爱  或是希望
Love or hope...
也许是吧
maybe?
Maybe.
不管是什么  我敢保证
Well, whatever it is, I can promise you
这对麦克斯韦尔·罗德而言太过强大
this is too powerful for Maxwell Lord.
我们必须找到他
We need to find this guy.
看看这个
Look at this.
如果日期正确  他出发去开罗了
If this date's right, he's going to Cairo.
开罗
Cairo?
(旅客票根)
对  大概是去谈合作吧
Yeah. Growth opportunity, you know?
"原油之王"
"King of Crude"?
旅程用时也太短了
How is this so fast?
现在有飞机能从这里直飞开罗吗
You have a plane that can fly from here to Cairo in one shot?
太厉害了
That is amazing.
是啊  但你不能坐飞机
Yeah, but we can't get you on one
因为你没有护照
because you don't have a passport.
我不想坐飞机
I don't want to get on one,
我想开飞机  我想开这个
I want to fly one. I want to fly the plane.
我想开这种飞机
I want to fly this plane.
行吗
Yeah?
我的天
Oh, my Betsy.
史蒂夫  这边
Hey, Steve, this way.
来了
Yeah.
瞧这大轮子
Look at these gams.
你挑一架吧
You wanna choose?
这架
This one.
我喜欢
I like it.
好了
Okay.
好的
不对
No.
搞定  很好
All right. Good, good.
燃料  燃料
Fuel, fuel, fuel.
好了  发动
Here we go. Engine.
豁出去了
Here goes nothing.
- 肯  - 怎么了
- Ken? - What?
有架飞机上跑道了
There's an aircraft on the runway.
什么叫"有架飞机上跑道了"
What do you mean, "There's an aircraft on the runway"?
呼叫进近管制员  这里是塔台
Approach, this is Tower.
有架未登记的飞机上了跑道
There's an unlisted aircraft on the runway.
你看到了吗
Are you seeing this?
- 能飞起来吗  - 当然  当然
- Can you get us up there? - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我得先加速
I just have to pick up speed first,
然后就起飞
and then I'll take off.
凭我的技术  他们休想找到我们
The way I fly, they will never find us.
- 我忘跟你说了  - 什么
- I forgot to tell you. - What?
雷达  三言两语解释不清
Radar. I can't explain now,
但我们去哪他们都能找到  黑夜里也一样
but they'll see us anywhere, even in the dark.
那他们会朝我们开枪吗
Well, will they shoot at us?
- 这下糟了  戴安娜  - 好吧
- Well, shit, Diana. - Right.
等等  我想到了
Wait. Shh! I know.
我知道了  集中精力
I know. Focus.
集中精力
Focus.
我父亲把整个天堂岛藏起来了
My father hid Themyscira from the world,
我一直想学他这一招
and I've been trying to learn how he did it.
学什么
Did what?
隐形术
Made something invisible.
但五十年来  我只成功过一次
But in 50 years, I've only done it once.
现在正是练习的好时机
Well, now's not a bad time to start trying.
- 能维持多久  - 我不清楚
- How long does it last? - I don't know.
我当时用的是咖啡杯
It was just a coffee cup...
而且被我弄没了
and I lost it.
进近管制员  那架飞机消失了
Approach, the aircraft has vanished.
你能看见它吗
Do you have eyes on it?
隐形飞机
An invisible jet.
那是什么
What's that?
没事
Oh, it's okay.
只是烟花而已
It's just fireworks.
今天是四号（美国独立日）  怪不得
The Fourth. Of course.
七月四号吗
The Fourth of July?
我有个主意
I got an idea.
你知道吗  就是这个
You know, it's the one thing.
我一直把这看作是你的象征
The one thing that's always been you to me.
什么
What?
飞行
Flight.
你的天赋
Your gift.
我永远也搞不懂
I'll never understand it.
其实...
Ah, it's...
真的很简单
It's so easy, really.
就是风和气流
It's wind and air
掌握如何驾驭气流  乘风而行
and knowing how to ride it, how to catch it.
融入天空
How to join with it.
道理都是相通的
Yeah. It's like anything, really.
好  谢了
Great, thanks.
找到了最后一个
Found the last one.
应该能让你看上一阵子
This should keep you busy for a while.
还有什么需要吗  咖啡
Anything else I can get you? Coffee?
茶
Tea?
还是我
Me?
你对我来说没用  我看完了
I don't need anything from you, and I'm done.
这就看完了
You're done?
说话不用这么刻薄吧
You don't have to be mean about it.
美女  你要去哪儿
Hey, babe. Where you going?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你真漂亮
Ooh, you're pretty.
慢点  美女
Hey, slow down, sexy.
你在跟我说话吗
You talking to me?
对  我在跟你说话
Yep. I'm talking to you.
你为什么不慢一点呢
Why don't you just slow down a bit, huh?
来吧  妹子
Come on, girl.
我不想  你懂我意思吗
I'd rather not. You know what I mean?
我不想跟你这种人有任何瓜葛
I'd rather not have anything to do with someone like you.
我想要你别再骚扰别人了
I'd rather you stop harassing people.
比如我
Like me.
你记得我吗
Do you remember me?
对了  对了
Oh, yeah, yeah.
我想起来了  上次到哪一步了
I remember. Where were we, huh?
不
No.
她说得对
She's right.
确实不难
It's not that hard.
我现在理解了
Yeah, I think I get it now.
确实是借力打力
His body weight does do all the work.
很简单
So easy.
我想
I think
我可以打上
I could do this...
一
all...
整
night...
夜
long!
芭芭拉
Barbara?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
少管闲事
Mind your business.
先生
Sir?
至少可以这么说
Your fortune the last few days
最近几天你的运气引人瞩目
has been impressive, to say the least.
但你为什么大老远跑来见我
But why come all this way to meet with me?
来见同道中人
To meet a peer.
同道中人
A peer?
不  罗德先生  我只是出于好奇
No, Mr. Lord. I only agreed to meet with you
才同意与你见面的
because I was curious.
没人能这么幸运  你是怎么做到的
No one gets that lucky. How did you do it?
在自我实现的道路上
On my journey to self-fulfillment...
我幸运地发现了一个秘密
I lucked into a secret.
愿望的秘密
The secret of the wish.
于是我许下愿望
So I wished for it.
或者别人为我许下愿望
Or someone wished for it for me.
告诉我你的愿望  殿下
Tell me what you wish for, Your Highness,
我来为你展示如何实现愿望
and I will show you how it works.
我的愿望无法实现
I wish for things one cannot attain.
什么愿望
Like what?
归还我的所有土地
All of my land to be returned.
我的故国
My ancestral realm.
比亚利安王朝
The Bialyian Dynasty.
并把所有胆敢践踏它的异教徒
And for all the heathens who dare trod upon it
永远拦在外面  让它重复昔日辉煌
to be kept out forever, so that its glory may be renewed.
这就是你的愿望吗
You wish for that?
这是我深切的愿望
I wish for that deeply.
你的愿望实现了
Your wish is granted.
作为回报  你的石油给我
And in return, I will take your oil.
你真把我逗乐了
You truly delight me.
你什么都不知道
You know so little.
我把石油都卖给沙特人了
I sold my oil to the Saudis.
你真是个傻子
You are a silly man.
那就把你的安保团队给我
Then I will take your security team
你一个人留在这里  失去全部防备
and leave you here with nothing to defend yourself
等着面对必将到来的怒火
against the wrath you most certainly will face.
殿下  奇迹发生了
停下  停车
Stop! Stop the car!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
立刻停下来  我跟你说
Stop what you're doing now! I'm telling you.
我命令你停下
I command you to stop!
停下
Stop!
停下  停下
Stop! Stop!
这堵不可思议  无法解释的墙似乎是
This unbelievable and unexplainable wall appears to
赛义德·本·阿比多斯酋长的杰作
somehow be the work of Emir Said Bin Abydos.
据政府报告说  突然出现了
The government is reporting old rulings have emerged
认可他的土地所有权的旧裁决书
acknowledging his claim to the land.
你还好吗
You okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
你一直说没事  但是
You keep saying that, but...
就是他
That was him!
他就是麦克斯·罗德
That was Max Lord.
停车
这辆车能卖给我们吗
请把他们解决掉
Get rid of them, please.
我来
I got this.
什么
What?
戴安娜
Diana!
刹车还能用
The brakes still work.
麦克斯·罗德
Max Lord,
你让自己和所有人都陷入了极大的危险
you're putting yourself and everyone else in grave danger.
你得把那块石头交给我
I need you to give me the stone.
石头去哪了
What happened to it?
就在你眼前
You're looking at it.
史蒂夫
Steve!
戴安娜
Diana!
离我们最近的石油大亨是谁
So who's the next closest person with oil?
这是我们的秘密
远离公路
戴安娜  戴安娜
Diana. Diana.
天啊  你这是怎么了
My God. What's going on with you?
这个匪夷所思的现象
A truly bizarre phenomenon
- 被称为神墙  - 发生了什么
- that is being called the Divine Wall. - What is happening?
这个无法解释的事件
It's an unexplainable event
导致埃及最贫穷社区的
that now sees Egypt's poorest communities
唯一淡水供应被切断
entirely cut off from their only supply of fresh water.
苏联宣布将认可酋长的权力
An already tense situation now escalating as the Soviet Union
使本就紧张的局势趋于白热化
announces they will recognize the Emir's claim.
- 不会吧  - 而埃及的长期盟友  美国
- Oh, no. - The United States, a longtime ally of Egypt,
则宣布要站在埃及政府一边
has declared their intention to side with the government.
国内方面也是一片混乱
Bedlam on the home front now as well
令人震惊的消息称
as the shocking news that
美国商人麦克斯·罗德
American businessman Max Lord
莫名占有了全球
has somehow come into possession
超过一半的石油储备
of over half of the world's oil reserves.
石油界的动荡导致
The instability in the oil community has resulted
全国的汽油需求暴涨
in a nationwide run on gas,
专家正做好准备迎接...
and experts are girding themselves...
喂
Hello?
芭芭拉  是我  戴安娜
Barbara, it's Diana.
- 你有没有...  - 有  算是有点眉目
- Did you... - Yeah. Uh, well, sort of.
我还没查明石头的具体来源
I haven't figured out exactly what the stone is,
但我找到了相关的历史照片
but I've found historical images of it.
哪里的照片
From where?
怪就怪在这里
That's the weird thing.
全球各地都有
From everywhere.
它首先出现在约四千年前的印度河谷
It first appeared in the Indus Valley almost 4,000 years ago.
公元前146年又在迦太基突然出现
It popped up again in Carthage in 146 BC.
公元4年  库施帝国
Kush, 4 AD.
罗慕路斯  西罗马帝国末代皇帝
Romulus, the last Emperor of Rome,
他在476年被刺杀时手里就拿着这块石头
he had it on him when he was assassinated in 476.
关于它的最后记载是在一座无名死城
The last record is in some previously unknown dead city
在玛雅古城附近
near Dzibilchaltun.
- 玛雅文明  - 是的
- The Mayans. - Yeah.
总之  调查到后面都是不了了之
Anyway, it just led me to a bunch of dead ends,
我的最后一条线索也不太可靠
and my last lead is not that promising.
是什么
What's that?
我找到了一张传单
A flier I found.
在大使馆拿的
Grabbed it at the embassy.
有个人声称自己是玛雅萨满
Some guy advertising to be a Mayan shaman.
但他在银河唱片行隔壁
But he literally teaches a course
非法占用的房子里授课
in a squat next to Galaxy Records.
- 他知道那块石头的事  - 他是这么说的
- And he knows about the stone? - So he says.
我明天早上过去看看
I'm gonna go there in the morning.
好  我们在那里见  谢谢你
Okay, we'll meet you there. And thank you.
怎么了
What is it?
那块石头走遍了世界
The stone has traveled the world
似乎随机出现在不同的地方
to seemingly random and different places,
- 但那些地方都有一个共同点  - 是什么
- but they all have one thing in common. - What?
那些文明都被彻底瓦解了
Their civilizations collapsed catastrophically.
找不出任何缘由
Without a trace as to why.
你不会觉得是那块石头...
You don't think the stone could have...
你确定吗
Do you?
我不知道  史蒂夫
I don't know what to think, Steve.
只能寄希望我是错的
I can only hope I'm wrong.
(银河唱片行)
巴巴吉德
Babajide?
- 来得真快  - 早
- That was fast. - Morning.
你好
Hello.
稍等
One second.
你是玛雅人吗
So you're a Mayan?
什么  我是世界公民
What? I'm a citizen of the world.
这上面写着你叫弗兰克
It says your name is Frank.
我了解的大多都是前世的事
Yeah. Most of what I know is a past-life thing.
所以不是玛雅人
So that's a no.
不过回答你的问题  没错
But to answer your question, yes.
我的曾曾祖父
My great-great-grandfather
给了我这个
left me this.
我对此一窍不通  但是有人警告过我
I don't know everything about it, but I have been warned
我最好别掺和进去
I'm better off that way.
我知道的是  这块石头在数月间
What I do know is, it destroyed our people
就毁灭了我们的族人
in a matter of months.
几个幸存者埋掉了石头
The few survivors, they buried the stone,
永世不得重见天日
never to be exhumed under any circumstances.
- 我能看看吗  - 请便
- Can I see that? - Be my guest.
怎么了
What?
说的是什么
What is it?
迪卡拉弗里亚·埃罗
Dechalafrea Ero.
那是什么
What's that?
一个很邪恶的神
A very bad God.
谎言之神  多洛斯  门达修斯
The God of Lies, Dolos, Mendacius,
欺骗公爵  他有很多名字
Duke of Deception. He's been called by many names.
但如果是他赋予了石头魔力
But if he's the one who empowered that stone,
其中肯定有诈
there has to be a trick.
谎言和实现愿望有什么关系
What do lies have to do with granting wishes?
它对我而言更像是块梦想石
It seems more like a Dreamstone to me.
许愿骗局
Wishes with a trick.
就跟《猴爪》里说的一样
"The Monkey's Paw."
小心你许下的愿望
Beware what you wish for.
它会实现你的愿望  但也会夺走你最宝贵的财富
It grants your wish, but takes your most valued possession.
戴安娜  你的力量
Diana, your powers.
这说不通啊
No, that doesn't make any sense.
有什么能比你的愿望更加宝贵
What's more precious than what you wish for?
我们要如何才能阻止
How do we stop this?
传说中说
The legend said
要想阻止它  只能毁了石头
it can only be stopped by destroying the stone itself
或者收回已经实现的愿望
or give back what was given.
我的族人做不到前者
My people couldn't do the first thing
也拒绝做后者
and refused to do the second.
如今文明已经灭亡
Now the culture's destroyed.
再也不复存在
Wiped from the face of the Earth.
没有人放弃自己的愿望吗
No one renounced their wish?
但石头已经被毁了
But the stone is already destroyed.
什么  什么时候
What? When?
"就在你眼前"
"You're looking at it."
"就在你眼前"  麦克斯·罗德是这么对我说的
"You're looking at it." That's what Max Lord said to me.
也许就是他
Maybe it's him.
他和石头化为一体了
He's become it somehow.
那怎么可能
But how would that happen?
如果他许的愿是...
I mean, if he wished for...
不  这太疯狂了  不可能
No, that's crazy. No.
如果我们毁了石头
If we destroy it,
消灭他
if we destroy him...
所有的愿望都会被收回
all the wishes go back.
你在说什么呢  不行
What are you talking about? No.
我才不要参与这事  不行
I'm not gonna be a part of that. No.
或者所有人都放弃愿望
Or if everyone renounces their wish.
肯定还有更好的办法
No, there has to be a better way.
不行
No.
她说得对
She's right.
我们现在掌握的信息还不够  不够
We don't know enough. We just don't know enough.
但可以确定的是
But what we do know is that
我们得在他实现更多愿望之前阻止他
we need to stop him before he grants any more.
阻止他可能还不够  戴安娜
Stopping him might not be enough, Diana.
已经有那么多愿望实现了
Wishes have been made.
芭芭拉
Barbara?
我根本就看不上他们
Like I want any of these people in the club anyway.
能把他们赶走吗
Can we tell them they're not invited?
不能  先生
No, sir.
- 联邦通讯委员会说我们不能...  - FCC啊
- The FCC said we couldn't... - Oh, the FCC.
我还BBB  FBD呢
The BBB, the FBD.
这是阻碍我成功的阴谋
It's a conspiracy against my success.
他们眼红了  没错  下一个是谁
They're jealous. That's why. Who's next?
- 是谁  - 你要找的人都来了
- Who's next? - Well, everyone you asked for,
钟赖  克拉吉先生
Lai Zhong, Mr. Khalaji,
还有抢了你广告时段的电视福音布道者
that televangelist who stole your slot.
你今晚还要陪阿里斯特
And you have Alistair for the night.
又要陪阿里斯特吗  我要陪他多少个周末啊
Alistair? Again? How many weekends do I have?
你说什么时候  今晚吗
What? What? When? Tonight?
他已经到了
He's here already.
他妈妈和男友在一起
His mom is with her boyfriend.
请钟先生进来
Send in Mr. Zhong, please.
给阿里斯特买匹小马
And buy Alistair a pony.
不  赛车  给他买辆赛车
No! A race car. Get him a race car.
我们开始吧  赖
Let's get to it, Lai.
告诉我
Tell me...
你想要什么
what do you want?
你的愿望是什么
What do you wish for?
我吗  说真的
Me? Truly?
苏联站在了伊朗一边
The Soviets have sided with Iran.
随着动荡的蔓延  伊拉克正准备自卫
Iraq is preparing to defend ourselves, as unrest spreads.
那你想要什么
And you need? What do you...
你的愿望是什么
What do you wish for?
性爱录像处理掉了
Consider the sex tape gone.
该死的  如果我得继续这样
And God darn it, if I have to keep doing this
一个接一个地问...
one by one, by one, by one...
- 你的健康状况如何  - 这个...
- How's your health? - Well...
算了
Forget that.
把你整个教会的教徒
But I will take your entire congregation
还有广告时段给我
and your time slot.
我问你
Let me ask you,
祈祷的时候  能不能让他们
when they pray, is there any way I could get all of them to...
都握住我的手
join hands with me?
让他们说"我希望"
And simply say, "I wish"
而不是"我祈祷"
rather than, "I pray"?
那样能行吗
Would that even work?
我不明...
I don't...
我要找个办法同时接触到很多人
I need to find a way to touch a lot of people at the same time.
先生  警察来了
Sir. The police are here.
他们认为你的安保团队没有行动权限
They're challenging the jurisdiction of your security team.
天啊
Oh, God!
这个不行  再找个人来
This isn't working. Bring in someone new.
还有我儿子
And my son.
你滚吧
You, beat it.
阿里斯特
Alistair!
我想你了  伙计
I've missed you, buddy.
过来  跟爸爸坐下来  对不起
Come. Sit down with Daddy. I'm sorry.
但是爸爸
But, your dad
正处在千钧一发的时刻
is on the absolute precipice of everything.
记得我跟你说过我会成为头号人物吗
Remember when I told you that I would be number one?
你记得吗  你爸爸
Do you remember? Your dad?
我现在胜利在望了
Well, I'm inches away.
我知道这不容易  我知道
I know it's hard. I know.
但听我说
But listen,
我知道你的愿望是什么  我的愿望和你一样
I also know what you wish for, and I wish for it, too.
你听到了吗  我的愿望和你一样
Do you hear that? I wish for it, too.
我只希望能和你在一起...
I just wish I could be with you...
不
No!
唯一的愿望不能这么用  阿里斯特
You don't use your one wish like that, Alistair.
你不能许愿要你已经拥有的东西
You don't wish for something that you already have.
你要许愿变得伟大  获得成功
You wish for greatness, for success.
这是我做这一切的目的
That's why I'm doing all of this.
难道你不明白我伟大就是你伟大吗
Don't you see that my greatness is your greatness?
那我希望你变得伟大
Then I wish for your greatness.
不  不
No. No!
谢谢你
Thank you.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
我向你保证  总有一天
And I promise you, one day,
一切都会有意义
everything is going to make sense.
总有一天  你会感谢我的
And one day, you'll thank me.
但是现在  我...
But right now, I, uh...
我要你和爱默生待在一起  好吗
Right now, I need you to stay here with Emerson, okay?
我很快就回来
I'll be back.
你待在这里
You stay here.
你  你
You. You.
什么事  先生
Yes, sir?
难道你不希望我今天能和总统会面吗
Don't you wish I had an audience with the President today?
我当然希望
Of course I do.
还有  很高兴你重视我的意见  先生
And can I tell you how happy I am that you value my opinion, sir?
等一下  我之前问过你的愿望吗
Wait a minute. Have I asked for your wish before?
昨天问过  我说想要一辆保时捷
Yesterday. A Porsche.
你们这些助理怎么都想要保时捷
What is it with you aides and Porsches?
你
You!
这边
This way.
路况如何
How's traffic?
堵死了
Terrible.
难道你不希望不堵吗
Don't you wish it wasn't?
你所到之处都像摩西分开红海一样畅通无阻
And that everywhere you went parted like the great Red Sea?
我当然希望  可惜那不可能
Of course I wish that. Sadly, ain't gonna happen.
你别跑
Hey, you! Stop!
快回家  外面不安全
Come on in. It's not safe.
沙特大使馆发生了暴动
There's a riot at the Saudi Embassy
街上到处都是保时捷横冲直撞
and there are Porsches racing up and down the street.
快走  这世界疯了
Come on. It's mad.
但是我的奶牛
But my cows.
我跟一个人说我想要一座农场
I told a man I wanted a farm.
我可没说是在这里
I didn't mean here.
等我一下
I'll be right back.
(特雷弗农场)
戴安娜  我知道这很难
Diana, I know it's been hard.
- 你不知道  你不懂  - 可是我们...
- You don't know. You don't. - But we...
不能再这样下去了
It can't go on like this.
- 我没法跟你谈这件事  - 我们不得不谈
- I can't talk about this. - We have to talk about it.
史蒂夫  我没法谈这件事
Steve, I can't talk about this!
我每天都在付出  付出一切
I give everything I have, every day.
我也很乐意
And I'm happy to.
唯独只有一个愿望
But this one thing...
一直以来我想要的只有你
You're all that I've wanted for so long.
我只想要你  只有你能让我快乐
You're the only joy I've had or even asked for.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry...
但这太荒唐了
but that's crazy.
这世界上多得是
There's a world out there full of
比我更好的男人
so many better guys, for one.
比如这家伙  他怎么样
I mean, how about this guy? How about him?
我不要他  我要你
I don't want him. I want you.
为什么就不能满足我这一个愿望  史蒂夫
Why, for once, can't I just have this one thing, Steve?
就这一个
This one thing.
我觉得我们别无选择
I'm not sure we have a choice.
我可以选择
Well, I do have a choice.
我不能放弃你  不能
And I can't give you up. I can't.
我也不会放弃  所以我们要阻止他
So I won't. So we need to stop him
想办法保住你
so we can figure that out.
一定有别的办法
There has to be another way.
一定有
Has to.
真不可思议
This is incredible.
那是什么
What's that?
我那个世界的
From my culture.
一个古代亚马逊战士的盔甲  我们最伟大的战士
The armor of an ancient Amazon warrior. One of our greatest.
很大啊  这是一整套吗
It's huge. This whole thing?
这是什么材料做的
What is it made out of?
我来告诉你
Here. Let me show you.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
你什么意思  我没有说谎
What are you talking about? I haven't lied.
套索不仅能让你说真话
The Lasso does more than just make you tell the truth.
还能让你看到真相
It can make you see it, too.
她叫阿斯忒瑞亚
Her name was Asteria.
她是我们最伟大的战士
She was our greatest warrior.
人类奴役亚马逊人之后  我母亲解放了我们
When mankind enslaved the Amazons, my mother freed us.
但是必须有人留下来挡住人潮
But someone had to stay behind to hold back the tide of men
其他人才能逃往天堂岛
so the others could escape to Themyscira.
我的族人用他们所有的盔甲
My people gave up all of their armor
为她制作出一套能抵挡全世界的战服
to make her one suit strong enough to take on the whole world.
阿斯忒瑞亚为他人的幸福牺牲了自己
And Asteria sacrificed herself for a better day for others.
太...
That's...
太不可思议了
That's incredible.
我刚来这里时找过她
When I came here, I searched for her.
但只找到她的盔甲
But all I could find was her armor.
什么情况
What is this?
他要去哪里
Where is he going?
坏了
Oh, no.
戴安娜  戴安娜  你要做什么
Diana, Diana! What are you doing?
- 你要去哪里  - 史蒂夫  我得去  你留下
- Where are you going? - Steve, I'm going. You need to stay.
不  不  听我说
No. No. Listen to me.
你的力量越来越弱了  戴安娜
You're getting weaker, Diana.
- 万一你摔下去呢  - 不会的
- What if you fall? - I won't.
有可能会  我们都说不好
You might. We don't know that.
一定有别的办法能进去
There has to be another way in.
你没事吧  总统先生
Everything okay, Mr. President?
没事
Yes.
感觉好奇怪  我...
Something very strange. I...
我以为我在另一个地方  突然...
I thought I was somewhere else entirely. Suddenly...
总之  很忙乱
Anyway. Hectic times.
你们回避一下
Give us a minute.
让一下
Excuse me.
- 卡尔  - 戴安娜
- Carl. - Diana.
- 你好  - 真荣幸
- Hi. - What a pleasure.
见到你真好  最近怎么样
Good to see you. How have you been?
- 很好  - 这是史蒂夫
- Good. - This is Steve.
史蒂夫  这是卡尔  我同事
Steve, this is Carl. My colleague.
那我们...
Shall we, uh...
好  走吧
Yeah, we shall.
抱歉  罗德先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Lord.
说实话  我都不知道这次会面是要谈什么
In fact, I don't even know what we're supposed to discuss.
就谈这个  总统先生
Exactly that, Mr. President.
这忙乱的日子  狂热的时代
These hectic days, hectic times.
还有你
And you.
这些并不算白宫里我最喜欢的半身像
These aren't exactly my favorite of the busts on display here,
但有张小画能排到我心目中的前十位
but it's a little picture of my top ten,
勉强可以算前五
maybe top five at a push.
前面的东西也许你会感兴趣
Oh, here's something up ahead that will interest you.
这些地砖
These are floor tiles
最初是简·林肯铺的
originally laid by none other than Jan Lincoln,
一位不出名的亚伯拉罕后代
a little-known descendent of Abraham.
你遇到麻烦了吧
You're having some troubles?
麻烦突然无处不在
Everywhere suddenly.
古巴  埃及
Cuba, Egypt,
还有国内
even here.
但苏联...
But Russia...
特别棘手
very troublesome.
我很感谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern,
但现在再多的钱也帮不了我们
but all the money in the world won't help us now.
我不是要给你钱
It's not money I'm offering.
你
You.
你是有信仰的人
You are a man of faith,
而我最近非常幸运
and I have been very blessed lately.
我想把我的运气分享给你
I want to share my blessing with you.
这是正面思考的力量
The power of positive thinking.
好了
Now...
总统先生  告诉我你需要什么
tell me, Mr. President, what do you need?
不是对着我说  而是对着宇宙说
And you're not speaking to me here, but to the universe.
你的愿望是什么
What do you wish for?
当然是想要更多
What is there to wish for but more?
更多核武器  比他们更多
More nuclear weapons. More than they have.
离他们更近
Closer to 'em.
只要我有那些核武器
If I just had that in place,
他们就必须听我们的
then they would have to listen to us.
想法不错  那我就帮你实现...
A nice thought. And I grant you...
天...
Oh, my...
你知道我要什么吗
And you know what I'd like?
我要你所有的势力  影响力  权力
I would want all of your power, influence, authority.
所有人对你的尊敬
All the respect you command
所有人对你的服从
and the command everyone must respect.
还能有什么
I mean, what else is there?
告诉你的手下
Now, tell your people I would appreciate
绝对不要来干涉我
absolutely no interference whatsoever.
没有税务和法律  没有任何限制
No taxes, no rule of law, no limits.
把我当成一个有绝对自治权的国家
Treat me like a foreign nation with absolute autonomy.
好的  先生
Very good, sir.
马上就办
Right away.
这是什么
What's this?
全球广播卫星
Global Broadcast Satellite.
这是个绝密计划  能让我们
Top-secret program that enables us
控制全世界所有广播系统
to override any broadcast system in the world
以防我们需要与敌国国民直接接触
in case we need direct contact with the people of an enemy state.
这是什么意思
So what does that mean?
你要控制所有人的电视吗
You're taking over everyone's TVs?
怎么控制
How?
使用粒子束技术
It uses particle beam technology,
就像星球大战计划一样
just like the Star Wars program.
据说在粒子信号覆盖的区域内
Apparently, it bathes the landscape in a signal of particles
粒子可以进入并操控所接触到的任何设备
that goes in and fiddles with any technology it touches.
不管设备新旧  想播放什么都可以
New or old. Broadcast whatever you want.
非常厉害
Very impressive.
你是说"接触"吗
You said "touches"?
发送的这些粒子...
As in the particles you are sending...
能接触一切吗
are touching everything?
这是个比喻
It's a figure of speech,
但没错
but yes.
他们就是这样跟我解释的
That's how it was explained to me.
我要立刻使用这颗卫星
I need immediate access to this satellite.
派直升机送我过去
And a chopper to get me there.
好的  先生  马上就办
Yes, sir. Right away.
你还真是神通广大
Well, aren't you resourceful?
趁你还没造成更多伤害  跟我走吧  麦克斯
Come with me before you do any more damage, Max.
不  我不走
No. I don't think so.
请把这个女人除掉
Remove this woman, please...
别手软
permanently.
- 你没事吧  - 不知道
- Are you okay? - I don't know.
不  史蒂夫  你不能用这个
No, Steve. You can't use that.
他们是无辜的
It's not their fault.
这招不错
That's neat.
芭芭拉
Barbara.
我不能让你这么做  戴安娜
I can't let you do this, Diana.
芭芭拉  什么
Barbara. What...
- 怎么...  - 我不能让你阻止麦克斯
- How... - I can't let you stop Max.
不是只有你的愿望会被收回
You're not the only one with something to lose.
没想到许愿像你一样...
Turns out wishing to be like you...
带来了惊喜
came with some surprises.
举起手来
Hands up.
- 举起手来  - 举起手来  举起手来
- Hands up. - Hands up, hands up.
举起手来
Hands up!
- 举起手来  - 快点
- Hands up! - Now! Now, now!
开火
Open fire!
真恩爱  保护自己的爱人
Oh, how sweet, defending your love. Huh?
你的愿望是什么  变成真正的活人吗
What do you wish for? Do you wanna be a real boy?
不
No.
我希望别跟你铐在一起  但还是铐上了
Just not to be handcuffed to you, but now I am.
我刚学会这招
I just learned that.
芭芭拉  住手
Barbara, stop!
听着
Listen.
你根本不明白自己许了什么愿望
You have no idea what you're dealing with.
我不是你想的那样
I'm not what you think.
你理解不了  也承受不了
You can't possibly understand or handle...
我理解不了吗
Oh, I can't possibly understand?
我这么傻
Dumb little old me.
又傻又可怜
Dumb little, poor little
没人在乎我
nothing, nobody me.
我根本承受不了
I couldn't possibly handle it.
不  芭芭拉  我不是这个意思
No, Barbara. That's not what I'm saying.
我倒是感觉得心应手
Well, I'm handling it beautifully.
我才不要放弃
And I'm not giving it back!
走啊
Go.
快跑
Run!
你们都停手
Everyone, stand down.
不许伤害她
Nobody hurts her.
他们伤害不了我
They couldn't if they tried.
你生来就拥有一切
You've always had everything,
而我这样的人一无所有
while people like me have had nothing.
现在轮到我了  你别想从我手中夺走
Well, now it's my turn. And you are not taking it from me. Ever!
但你付出了什么代价
But what is it costing you?
我付出了什么代价
What is it costing me?
如果跟猴爪一样  那么代价与愿望同等
If it's the monkey's paw, it takes as much as it gives.
对  你变强大了  但是
Yes, you're strong, but...
你失去了什么  芭芭拉
what did you lose, Barbara?
你的热情  你的快乐
Where's your warmth, your joy,
你的人性呢
your humanity?
你攻击了无辜的人  芭芭拉  看看你自己
You're attacking innocent men, Barbara. Look at yourself.
别说我了
Forget about me.
你付出了什么代价
What is it costing you?
明白了吧
That's right.
好好习惯一下吧
Get used to it.
如果你去追捕麦克斯·罗德
If you go after Max Lord...
或者伤害他
or hurt him in any way,
我会消灭你
I will destroy you.
芭芭拉
Barbara!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
来
Come here.
能加一个人吗
Room for one more?
先生  你得等等
Sir, you need to wait.
- 总统现在正在开会  - 我们要见总统
- The President has a meeting right now. - We need to see the President.
他必须明白
He needs to be told.
- 事关生死存亡  - 怎么回事
- This is a matter of life and death. - What is going on?
苏联的预警系统发现了我们的新核武器
The Soviets' early detection system picked up our new nukes.
什么新核武器
What new nukes?
一百枚核弹头刚被激活  准备发射
A hundred warheads just went online, ready to launch.
他们认为这是战争行为
They're taking this as an act of war.
正在准备反击
Prepping to return fire.
反击  什么
Return? What?
我们什么都没做
We haven't done anything.
但看起来不是这样
That's not how it looks.
如果处境对调  我们早就反击了
And we'd fire for less.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
你闯红灯了  你看都没看
You blew through that light right there! You didn't even see!
你眼瞎吗
How do you not see that?
随着美苏两国
Riots across the world erupting
终止对话  宣布开战
as America and the Soviet Union end communication,
世界各地暴乱四起
declaring war!
没人知道前因后果
No one knows any more than that.
但是空前危机当前
But as you can imagine with what's at stake,
华盛顿特区市中心陷入了疯狂之中
there has been madness down here in downtown Washington, D.C.
国民警卫队已出动...
The national guard has been brought in...
注意  注意
Attention! Attention!
根据行政命令
By executive order,
所有民众必须立即撤离
all civilians must immediately evacuate
西北3街与西北12街
the Pennsylvania Avenue corridor
之间的宾夕法尼亚大道路段
between 3rd and 12th streets northwest.
我们面临的是大灾难的末期
It is the final days of tribulation that is happening to us now.
你们看到自己罪行的恶果了吗
Can you see what your sinfulness has done?
你们的贪婪
Your greed?
你得做点什么  你得做点什么
You gotta do something! You gotta do something!
快  这边  快
Come on! This way! Come on!
莱丽
Riley!
全体人员
All units.
莱丽
Riley!
我们需要帮助
We need help.
- 到处都一片混乱  - 莱丽
- It's chaos out here. - Riley!
你想让我怎么办  我不知道该怎么办
What do you want me to do? I don't know what to do.
帮帮我
Somebody help me.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
戴安娜
Diana.
戴安娜  听我说
Diana, listen to me.
我度过了精彩的一生
I had a great life.
史蒂夫
Steve...
而你让我的人生更美好了
And you only made it better.
但你知道应该做什么
But you know what you need to do.
这个世界需要你
The world needs you.
- 好吗  - 不
- All right? - No.
我再也不会爱上别人
I'll never love again.
我希望这话不是真的
I pray that isn't true.
这个世界那么大  那么美好
There's a wonderful, big world out there.
这个疯狂的新世界
This crazy new world.
我很高兴能来看一看
And I am so happy I got to see it...
但它值得你拯救
but it deserves you.
我说不出再见
I can't say goodbye.
你不用说
You don't have to.
我已经不在了
I'm already gone.
我会永远爱你  戴安娜
I'll always love you, Diana,
无论我在哪里
no matter where I am.
我爱你
I love you.
我放弃我的愿望
I renounce my wish.
很简单
It's easy.
就是风和气流
It's only wind and air...
驾驭气流
and how to ride it.
乘风而行
How to catch it.
你也许愿了  是吧
You made a wish too, huh?
愿望很狡猾  不是吗
They're a bitch, aren't they?
必须付出代价
Make you pay a price, but
但我从不遵守规则
I've never been one for rules.
所幸我有逆转的办法
Luckily, I have a way to reverse it.
永不满足才能生存
The answer is always more.
但每人只能许一个愿望
But you only get one wish.
但实现愿望的人是我
But I, my dear, grant the wishes.
所以我能要求回报
So I take what I want in return.
不管我想要什么  都能从别人身上夺取
There's nothing in this world someone doesn't have.
我会重塑我的健康  用一个个愿望换一个个器官
I'll rebuild my health, wish by wish, organ by organ...
如果有必要的话
if I have to.
我将无人能敌
I'll be invincible.
告诉我
Tell me,
你想要什么
what do you want?
我现在很慷慨
I'm feeling generous.
我不想再像任何人一样了
I don't want to be like anyone anymore.
我想成为头号人物
I want to be number one.
顶级掠食者
An apex predator,
前所未有的存在
like nothing there's ever been before.
我喜欢你的想法
I like the way you think.
继续
Go on.
你应该收到命令了吧
You heard we were coming, I presume?
我一次能控制多少广播信号
How many broadcasting signals can I take over at once?
你想控制多少都行  先生
Well, as many as you like, sir.
我要控制所有的信号
I'll take all of them.
所有的吗
All of them?
难道你不希望我能成功吗
And I sure wish this works for me. Don't you?
当然希望  先生
Yes, sir.
灯光  摄像机
Lights, camera...
12号  9号  16号  开始传送
Okay, stations 12, 9, 16, go transmit.
立即传送  16号  9号  12号  收到了吗
I need it now. 16, 9, 12. Do you receive?
收到  最大功率
Copy. Maximum power.
好  准备开始
Okay. Moving forward now.
全球传送倒计时  五  四  三  二
Global transmission in five, four, three, two...
全世界的人民
Citizens of the world,
容我介绍一下自己
allow me to introduce myself.
我是麦克斯·罗德
I am Max Lord,
我将要改变你们的人生
and I'm here to change your life.
你们只需要
All you have to do...
许下愿望
is make a wish.
任何愿望
Anything you want.
任何梦想  都能实现
Anything you dream of, you can have it.
只要敢想
If you can dream it...
爸爸
Daddy?
就能实现
...you can achieve it.
只要看着我的双眼
So just look into my eyes...
许下愿望
and make a wish.
任何梦想  都能实现
Anything you dream of, have it.
我想成名
快许愿吧
Right now.
你想大富大贵吗
Do you want to be rich?
你想权力在握吗
Do you want to be powerful?
行吧  随你怎么说
Yeah, yeah. Whatever you say.
- 大声许愿  - 你知道我有什么愿望吗
- Say it out loud! - You know what I wish?
- 什么愿望  - 我希望你们这帮爱尔兰混蛋
- What? What? - I wish all you Irish bastards
通通被赶回老家
would get sent back to where you came from!
是吗  那我希望你去死
Yeah? Well, I wish you'd drop dead!
看看身边
Look around you.
快许愿吧
Make your wish!
抓住机会
Take what's yours.
任何愿望
Whatever you want,
都能实现
you can have it.
我希望有一百万美元
I wish for a million dollars.
我们要有自己的导弹
我希望成为国王
我希望我们有核武器
许下愿望
Wish for it.
任何愿望
Anything you want.
任何梦想  都能实现
Anything you dream of, have it.
好
Yes.
我能听到
I can hear it.
我听到了
I hear you.
说吧
Yes, say it.
大声许愿
Say it out loud.
没错  "我希望"
That's right. "I wish."
拿去  拿去吧  都是你们的
Take it. Take it. It's all yours.
都是你们的
It's all yours for the taking!
作为交换  你的健康和你的体力给我
And I... I take your health and your strength.
你的愤怒和你的体魄给她
Give her your rage and your prowess.
你的力量给我
And I take your power.
你的生命力给我
I take your life force.
好
Yes.
Yes!
没错
That's right.
你们做得很好
You're doing great.
都是你们的
It's all yours.
我希望你在我身边  爸爸
I wish you were here, Daddy.
我希望你回来  爸爸  求你了
I wish you'd come back. Daddy, please!
- 你们只要许下愿望  - 我还在这里  爸爸
- All you have to do is wish for it. - I'm still here, Daddy.
爸爸  求你了
Daddy, please!
芭芭拉
Barbara.
你做了什么
What did you do?
不
No.
你放弃了你的愿望
You renounced your wish.
不得不放弃  你也要放弃
I had to. And so do you.
谎言不会带来好结果  芭芭拉
Nothing good is born from lies, Barbara.
我们在浪费宝贵的时间
We're wasting precious time.
到了现在  你还是瞧不起我
Even now, patronizing me.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
我知道你还有理智  求你了
I know you're in there. Please.
求你了  放弃你的愿望
Please, renounce your wish.
结束了
It's over.
求你了
Please!
放弃你的愿望
Renounce your wish.
决不
Never!
那我很抱歉
Then I'm so sorry.
没错
That's right.
快许愿吧
Just wish for it.
都是你们的
It's yours now.
你们只要大声许愿
All you have to do is say it out loud.
许下愿望  任何愿望
Make a wish. Any wish.
看着我的双眼
Look into my eyes,
你们梦寐以求的一切  都能实现
and everything you've been waiting for, it's all yours.
你来迟了
You're too late.
实现了
Granted.
Granted!
实现了
- 实现了  - 你为什么要这么做
- Granted. - Why are you doing this?
你拥有的还不够多吗
Don't you have enough?
为什么不要更多
Why not more?
为什么不许愿要更多
Why not wish for more?
但他们不知道你夺走了什么
But they don't know what you're taking from them.
想要就是想要
We want what we want.
你也许愿了
Just like you did.
许愿吧
So make a wish.
很好
Very good.
实现了
Granted.
太迟了  戴安娜
It's too late, Diana.
他们已经听到我的话
They already heard me.
已经许下愿望
Already wished!
那些还没许愿的人
And those that haven't yet...
也会许愿的
They will!
实现了
Granted.
可怜的戴安娜
Poor Diana.
为什么要逞英雄呢
Why be such a hero?
只要加入我的阵营
You could have kept your pilot and your powers,
你就能同时拥有爱人和力量
if only you'd join me.
要不要重新考虑一下
Wanna reconsider?
我是个宽宏大量的人
I'm a forgiving man!
你想要他回来吗
You want him back?
只要许愿就行了
Just say the word.
你可以拥有一切
You can have it all!
只要你想要
You just have to want it!
我最想要的就是他
I've never wanted anything more.
但他已经不在了
But he's gone...
那才是真相
and that's the truth.
万事皆有代价
And everything has a price.
而我不愿付这个代价
One I'm not willing to pay.
再也不了
Not anymore.
这个世界本来就很美好
This world was a beautiful place just as it was...
没人能拥有一切
and you cannot have it all.
你只能拥有真相
You can only have the truth.
真相就足够了
And the truth is enough.
真相是美好的
The truth is beautiful.
所以看看这个世界
So look at this world...
看看你的愿望让世界付出了什么代价
and look at what your wish is costing it.
你一定要成为英雄
You must be the hero.
只有你能挽救一切
Only you can save the day.
如果你想拯救这个世界
Renounce your wish
那就放弃你的愿望
if you want to save this world.
我为什么要放弃
Why would I...
好不容易轮到我
when it's finally my turn?
这个世界是属于我的
The world belongs to me!
你阻止不了我  谁也阻止不了我
You can't stop me. No one can!
我不是在对你说话
I wasn't talking to you.
我是在对世界上其他所有人说话
I was talking to everyone else.
因为并非只有你遭受痛苦
Because you're not the only one who has suffered.
想要更多
Who wants more.
想要逝者归来
Who wants them back.
想要不再害怕
Who doesn't want to be afraid anymore.
不再孤独
Or alone.
停下
Stop!
切断信号  停下
Cut the signal! Stop!
不再恐惧
Or frightened.
不再无力
Or powerless.
因为并非只有你
'Cause you're not the only one
希望世界变成截然不同的样子
who imagined a world where everything was different.
终于变得更好
Better. Finally.
变成一个能感受到爱
A world where they were loved
感受到理解与认同的世界
and seen, and appreciated.
终于
Finally.
天呐  他是谁
Oh, my God. Who is he?
他连英语都不会说
He doesn't even speak English.
他吃的是什么
What is he eating?
快看他的鞋子
Look at his shoes!
怪胎
Weirdo!
(黑金合作社)
可是你为此付出了什么代价呢
But what is it costing you?
你看到真相了吗
Do you see the truth?
爸爸
Daddy!
不断有新的导弹出现
我们别无选择
准备发射
俄国人正在发射导弹
The Russians are launching.
我们受命进行反击
We've got orders to counter.
好吧
All right, all right.
阿里斯特
Alistair!
紧急警报
Emergency alert.
请在四分钟内进入避难所
You have four minutes to find shelter.
阿里斯特
Alistair!
儿子
My son!
保持镇定  留在室内
Stay calm and stay indoors.
阿里斯特
Alistair!
爸爸  爸爸
Daddy! Daddy!
救救我  爸爸
Help me, Daddy!
- 这不是演习  - 爸爸
- This is not a test. - Daddy!
爸爸
Daddy!
剩余一分钟
One-minute warning.
等等  儿子
Wait. My son!
我能看到我儿子
I can see my son!
救救他  麦克斯
Save him, Max.
我必须救我儿子
I have to save my son.
爸爸
Daddy!
阿里斯特
Alistair.
爸爸
Daddy!
阿里斯特
My... Alistair.
我放弃我的愿望
I renounce my wish!
I renounce my wish.
导弹在不断消失  长官
We have missiles disappearing, sir.
是的  长官  屏幕上的导弹信号正在消失
Yes, sir. They are vanishing from our screen.
最新消息
Only just hearing now
苏联和美国之间的停战
that a ceasefire between the Soviet Union and the United States
避免了一场全球核危机
has averted a global nuclear crisis.
我放弃我的愿望
I renounce my wish.
- 我放弃我的愿望  - 我放弃我的愿望
- I take back my wish. - I renounce my wish.
阿里斯特
Alistair!
爸爸
Daddy!
- 爸爸  - 阿里斯特
- Daddy! - Alistair!
阿里斯特
Alistair.
阿里斯特  阿里斯特
Alistair, Alistair.
对不起  宝贝
I'm so sorry, baby.
幸好我许愿要你回来
I'm so glad I wished you'd come.
我就知道会实现的
I knew it would work.
不
No.
不是愿望让我回来的
That is not why I'm back.
不
No.
我一直都在骗你
I've been lying to you.
我不是大人物
I'm not a great guy.
事实上  我是个糟糕透顶的窝囊废
In fact, I'm a pretty messed up, loser guy.
我还铸成了大错
And I made terrible mistakes.
但是你
But you...
你永远也不必许愿让我爱你
you don't ever have to make a wish for me to love you.
我回来是因为我爱你
I'm here because I love you.
我...
I just...
我希望  我祈祷有一天
I just wish and I pray that, one day,
我能让你为我感到骄傲
I'll be able to make you proud enough
能让你原谅我
that you'll be able to forgive me.
能让你爱我
And love me.
因为我根本不值得骄傲  阿里斯特
Because I'm nothing to be proud of, Alistair.
我不需要你让我感到骄傲
I don't need you to make me proud.
我一直都爱你  爸爸
I already love you, Daddy.
你是我爸爸
You're my dad.
- 抱歉  - 抱歉
- Sorry. Sorry. - Sorry.
没事  没事
It's okay. It's okay.
太美了
So beautiful.
抱歉  我在自言自语
Sorry. Just talking to myself.
没关系
It's all right.
只是感叹
It's just that...
这世上的美好数不胜数
It's wonderful. It's so many things.
是啊
Yeah.
我懂你的意思
I know what you mean.
我喜欢你的...
I like your...
我喜欢你的打扮
I like your outfit.
你喜欢...
You like...
谢谢
Thanks.
我的朋友们
You know, my friends...
都笑话这身打扮  但还挺合适的吧
they kinda tease me about it, but it works, right?
- 你穿着很好看  - 谢谢
- You look great. - Thank you.
你的话我很受用
You just made my day.
- 节日快乐  有缘再会  - 节日快乐
- Happy holidays. See you around. - Happy holidays.
数不胜数
So many things.
美不胜收
So, so many things.
《神奇女侠1984》
小心
Look out!
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 妈  你看好她  - 好
- Mom, would you take her? - Yeah.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
打扰一下  我必须感谢你  怎么称呼...
Excuse me. Please, you have to let me thank you, Miss...
阿斯忒瑞亚
Asteria.
这名字真好听
That's a beautiful name.
我那个世界的
It's from my culture.
实在太感谢了  你救了我女儿
I can't thank you enough. I mean, you saved my daughter.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
简单的借力打力罢了  熟能生巧
It's just a simple shift of weight. Takes practice.
不过我从很久以前就开始了
But I've been doing this a long time.